Amal Majeed

Regina, SK. | +1-(306)-520-3484 | amal.majeed.mec@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/amal-majeed-a31543105/ | https://github.com/amalmajeed

Objective

Computer science masters degree graduate who brings a total of 2 years of professional IT experience working full time and as an intern in large scale software, support engineering and data analyst environments. Experience writing python scripts, node js and web development with regular HTML, CSS and javascript. Focusing on pursuing a software developer career track and looking for open full time roles for the same.

Work Experience

JUNIOR ANALYST CO-OP INTERN | GOVERNMENT OF SASKATCHEWAN | 04/2020 - 12/2020 | REGINA, SK, CANADA.

- · Member of the Labour market intelligence team for the Ministry of Immigration and Career training.
- · Roles and responsibilities :
 - Developed an automation script in python 3 for data extraction and initial parsing for the survey of employment, payments and hours data from Statistics Canada and reduced prior operational procedure time by 10%.
 - Created monthly data driven reports from the major employment and labour force survey releases from Statistics Canada using Python Microsoft excel and power BI.
 - Part of a team project to develop a power BI based COVID-19 business response tool that can be
 used by the consultants within the ministry to give accurate responses to business owner queries.
- **Technologies used**: Python 3, Microsoft Excel pivot tables, Power BI, StatsCan Web Data Service (APIs), Microsoft Powerpoint, Microsoft Windows.

SUPPORT ENGINEER II | AMAZON DEVELOPMENT CENTRE (INDIA) PRIVATE LIMITED | 07/2017 - 08/2018 | HYDERABAD, TS, INDIA.

- Member of the E-commerce operational excellence team and worked as the service availability team focal for Identity Services.
- · Roles and responsibilities:
 - Troubleshot server related issues such as CPU over utilisation, service latency, error or warning log threshold breaches etc using Amazon's ticketing tool and remote SSH within the SLA time.
 - Provided weekly frontline on-call support for high severity tickets for eCommerce service groups for the above mentioned issues.
 - Attended regular meetings with amazon IdentityServices developer and devOps teams to discuss the fixes for the recurring web service issues and implement code revisions to mitigate them.
 - o Conducted stress performance tests for server fleets before scaling or descaling them, prior to peak online sale events such as 'Black Friday', 'Cyber Monday' and 'PrimeDay'.
- **Technologies used**: Python, bash shell, Javascript (greasemonkey) MacOS, Amazon internal tools and services (cloudwatch monitors and portal, herd customer order workflow portal, fleet management portal etc).

PROJECT INTERN | TATA ELXSI | 05/2016 - 07/2016 | THIRUVANANTHAPURAM, KL, INDIA.

- · Worked with the Jaguar Landrover Offshore Development centre team at Tata Elxsi.
- · Roles and responsibilities :
 - Developed a python script to automate the restructuring of vehicular sensor data into an XML format.
 - Conducted a study and prepared a report on sample use cases for adopting the new version of AUTOSAR based on service oriented architecture, for Jaguar Landrover vehicles.
- **Technologies used**: Python, Microsoft Windows, Windows CMD shell, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, XML.

Education

MASTER OF SCIENCE (M.SC) | 09/2019 - 04/2022 | UNIVERSITY OF REGINA

- · Major: Computer Science, GPA: 3.55/4
- · Sample project: React Native project (Kanban Notes) Kanban/To do board app (Mobile computing)
- **Related coursework**: Data analysis from the internet, Mobile computing, Human computer communications, Computer systems security, Artificial Intelligence.

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY (B.TECH) | 07/2013 - 05/2017 | COCHIN UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

- · Major: Computer Science & Engineering, GPA: 3.52/4
- · Sample Project: Python Django project (IDGen): ID card generator web app for college.
- **Related coursework**: Data structures and algorithms, Artificial neural networks, Operating systems, Discrete mathematics, Database management systems, Computer networks.

Skills & Knowledge

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE

Most used: Python, Node js , HTML , CSS and Javascript.

Familiarity: React js, React Native, AWS (amazon web services), Django MVC framework, Unit Testing, REST APIs, SQL.

Working knowledge: Git, mongoDB, HTTP and TCP/IP Stack, UNIX, Windows and macOS operating systems, Visual Studio, bash shell, Microsoft office (excel, word etc), automation (cron jobs etc), data structures and algorithms.

SOFT SKILLS

- · Strong communication and presentation skills.
- · Fast learner.
- · Task prioritization and time management graduate teaching assistant experience.
- Team work and leadership skills experience working with academic and technical groups of different sizes and mentoring support engineering interns, sales associates and peer groups of fellow students.